NWLB Records 5310
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
NWLB Records
1944
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
United States. National War Labor Board (1942-1945)
5310
0.83 cubic feet
0.8 linear ft.
Transcripts, reports, pamphlets.
This collection consists of statements, exhibits and documents presented to a panel hearing of the NWLB in 1943 on a petition from the United Steelworkers of America for a wage adjustment which exceeded the 15 percent increase adopted in the so-called "Little Steel Formula."
5596464
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 14, 2005
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 30, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5241: National Wartime Conference of the Professions, the Sciences, the Arts and the White Collar Fields 5289: AoM Records 5309: NWLB Files 5311: NWLB Region II Office Files and Cases 5312: NWLB Files 5313: NWLB Southern Coal Procedures Records 5314: NWLB Non-Ferrous Metals Commission Records 5699: William Bardsley Collection of United States National Recovery Administrations and National War Labor Board Printed and Mimeographed Documents 5752 mf: Papers of the National War Labor Board on Microfilm 5780/085: ILGWU National War Labor Board case files 6127m: National War Labor Board Executive Meeting Transcript
Steel industry and trade -- Employees -- United States; Wages -- Steel industry -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; United States. National War Labor Board (1942-1945); United States. National War Labor Board (1918-1919)
5596464
- United Steelworkers of America and United States Steel Corp. - Brief Submitted by the United Steelworkers of America., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- United Steelworkers of America and United States Steel Corp. - Statement of T. F. Patton, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  April 25th
- United Steelworkers of America and United States Steel Corp. - Pertinent Documents Relation to the National Economic Stabilization Program, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- United Steelworkers of America and United States Steel Corp. - Statement of Dr. Donald R. G. Cowan with regard to Wages and the Cost of Living, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- United Steelworkers of America and United States Steel Corp. - Statement of Dr. Jules Backman, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- United Steelworkers of America and United States Steel Corp. - Pertinent Documents Relating to the Proceedings Prior to the Beginning of Hearings Before the Panel, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- United Steelworkers of America and United States Steel Corp. - Statement of C. A. McLain with regard to the National Economic Stabilization Program and the Wage Demands of the Union, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- United Steelworkers of America and United States Steel Corp. - Statement of Dr. Jules Backman: The Claims of the Union with regard to the Economic Position of the Workers, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  April 27th
- United Steelworkers of America and United States Steel Corp. - Statement of Dr. Jules Backman: The Claims of the Union with regard to the Economic Position of the Worker Part II, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  May 16th
- United Steelworkers of America and United States Steel Corp. - Statement of F. R. Brugler: Corporate Profits and Wages, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  May 17th
- United Steelworkers of America and United States Steel Corp. - Statement of Bradford B. Smith with regard to the Guaranteed Wage, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  May 18th